<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>San Diego Mortgage Video Blog with PrimeLending</title>
    <description>Our mission at PrimeLending is to be your best resource for the San Diego mortgage process. Whether you’re a first-time homebuyer, in the market for another home, or you’re looking to renovate or refinance, PrimeLending makes your process simple, transparent and rewarding. For us, it really is Home Loans Made Simple®.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 21:35:24 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 21:35:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Consider Before Buying an Investment Property</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yJ5AnkDkpbY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s what to consider if you’re thinking of buying an investment property in 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of buying an investment property in 2020, moving forward with the purchase mostly depends on your long-term objectives. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re able, Michael Radi, our branch manager, always recommends buying a two-, three-, or even four-unit property. One of the most important factors to consider in San Diego County is home prices. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to buy a multi-unit property, you’ll have to put more money down based on the loan program you use. There are also restrictions to contend with in terms of the size of your loan. Reserve requirements are another factor to consider with these properties—you need several months’ worth of payments in reserve to qualify. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Consult with an experienced loan officer so they can outline all available opportunities.%20http://localhost:4000/what-to-consider-before-buying-an-investment-property.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Consult with an experienced loan officer so they can outline all available opportunities.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the primary reasons buying a multi-unit property is a great investment is because &lt;strong&gt;you have multiple renters helping to pay down your mortgage.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re a first-time buyer, this will allow you to buy a larger property as a future investment nest egg. Technically, you only have to live in the home a year before you’re free to buy another investment property or long-term primary residence. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you do anything, though, consult with an experienced loan officer so they can outline all available opportunities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about this or any other lending topic or would like to schedule a consultation, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 14:34:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-to-consider-before-buying-an-investment-property.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-to-consider-before-buying-an-investment-property.html</guid>
        
        <category>Budgeting for a Home</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lending Rules: Second Home vs. Investment Property</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/swqAId78JyE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How will you be using that additional home you’re buying? Here’s why underwriters want to know the answer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re exploring the difference between buying a second home and buying an investment property. Typically, there are different rules at play for each scenario. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One clear example is the down payment: &lt;strong&gt;You can buy a second home with as little as 10% down.&lt;/strong&gt; However, underwriters use a set of guidelines to make sure that your property will be used as a residence and not as an investment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’ll ask you questions to confirm you’re not going to rent out the property. They’ll even go so far as to double-check your tax returns to make sure that’s the case. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’ll also want to know why you’re buying a second home. Perhaps you’re buying in a resort community, or your job demands that you work in a certain area for a certain amount of time each year. Is the home at least 100 miles away from your primary residence? Have you been a landlord in the past? These are all common questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Second homes generally have a better interest rate than investment properties.%20http://localhost:4000/lending-rules-second-home-vs-investment-property.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Second homes generally have a better interest rate than investment properties.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Underwriters get particular because, &lt;strong&gt;when you buy an investment property, they ask for a minimum of 15% down&lt;/strong&gt; (some increase it to 20% down because not all mortgage insurance companies will cover that purchase when you also buy an investment property). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the condition of the home? How much are the rents going for in that area? If it is currently rented, typically &lt;strong&gt;most mortgage companies let you use 75% of the rental income to help offset that mortgage.&lt;/strong&gt; For instance, if that home is rented for $1,000, most mortgage companies will let you use $750 to apply to offset the mortgage on that particular home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second homes generally have a better interest rate than investment properties, but it is a case-by-case system; reach out to a seasoned mortgage professional for the proper guidance in helping you determine what makes the most sense. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope to answer more questions like this in the near future, and if you have other questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send an email. We’re always here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 12:57:18 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/lending-rules-second-home-vs-investment-property.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/lending-rules-second-home-vs-investment-property.html</guid>
        
        <category>Budgeting for a Home</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unison: A Revolutionary Program for Buyers*</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/P6QmHAquaes?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s what you should know about PrimeLending’s exciting new down payment assistance product, Unison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a lot of consumers are aware of the product I’m sharing today, especially first-time homebuyers. There are a variety of down payment assistance programs(1) available across the country, so exploring them all can be confusing. The specific type that I’m highlighting here acts like shared equity, and here’s what I mean by that: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you’re looking for a home and happen to come across one that’s a little bit too expensive; your down payment would naturally have to be greater. Typically, consumers shy away, settle for something more affordable, and adjust to less square footage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Unison is one of the most amazing products on the market now.%20http://localhost:4000/unison-a-revolutionary-program-for-buyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Unison is one of the most amazing products on the market now.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if your heart is set on that larger house? Maybe you just can’t pass up its unique layout. Believe it or not, you do have options. PrimeLending currently offers a program called Unison, which matches your down payment. For example, if you come to the table with 10% down (which, by itself, would not be enough for this larger home), Unison will come in and match that 10%. Well, what’s the benefit of this, and how does it work? Here are some points to know: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. It gives you more purchasing power on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; Where you once saw upfront costs as barriers blocking you from your perfect home, you now see possibility. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Unison wants to be a shared equity partner with you.&lt;/strong&gt; They match your down payment up to 10%, helping you close on the home. Then, in three years or more, you would only have to pay PrimeLending a percentage (30%) of the amount by which your home has increased in value in order to pay them out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, you get to enjoy the house, and there’s no interest accumulating or payments necessary in the meantime. Also, you don’t have to pay them out after three years. You can keep the shared equity for the entire life of the loan or until you sell the home, at which point you would pay them out at the required percentage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This product is on the market for the consumer’s benefit.&lt;/strong&gt; Do note that there are a lot more details involved, but the bottom line is that Unison is one of the most amazing products out there on the market right now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on this product, please contact us here at PrimeLending. We’re always happy to get you up to speed on everything we have to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Disclaimers&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) Certain restrictions apply. Not available in all areas. Please contact your PrimeLending loan officer for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* Unison is an independent investor and is not affiliated with any bank or lender. Unison offers its products with a variety of lender partners, as the lender partner offers programs without Unison deals. Each of the Unison programs and lender programs may be used independently of each other. Unison HomeBuyer Agreements and Unison HomeOwner Agreements are provided exclusively by Unison Agreement Corp., a wholly-owned subsidiary of Real Estate Equity Exchange, Inc., dba Unison. Certain restrictions apply. “Unison” is a trademark of Real Estate Equity Exchange, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 13:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/unison-a-revolutionary-program-for-buyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/unison-a-revolutionary-program-for-buyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Budgeting for a Home</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Let Unpermitted Work Affect Your Options</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QnX6o6OYpVE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you done something unpermitted to your property, like adding a certain unit? Today’s message is for you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we begin 2020, it’s important for you as a consumer to be aware of all the opportunities out there for you now. There’s a variety of products we offer at PrimeLending, but there is one product in particular in which many people aren’t aware. I’m excited to share it with you today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a property will have a certain unit installed in it (or contract work done to it) that is unpermitted by the county. After anything unpermitted is done, the owners will find it difficult to refinance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Most banks will tell you, ‘We’re not going to touch this.’%20http://localhost:4000/dont-let-unpermitted-work-affect-your-options.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Most banks will tell you, ‘We’re not going to touch this.’”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you have a single-family residence, but you built a unit in the back, you’ve likely done something unpermitted that can affect your refinancing options. Most banks will tell you, “We’re not going to touch this.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;PrimeLending offers an appraisal that takes into consideration only the &lt;em&gt;permitted&lt;/em&gt; items on a lot.&lt;/strong&gt; We will be able to do the loan without counting that unpermitted unit as part of the value. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself in a situation like this and would like to know details on it, feel free to give us a call at PrimeLending. We’re experts on these kinds of financing options and we’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 08:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-let-unpermitted-work-affect-your-options.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/dont-let-unpermitted-work-affect-your-options.html</guid>
        
        <category>Refinance</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Factors for Future Real Estate Investors to Consider</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tDSAAX3mOYQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are three things you can expect a lender to look into if you’re thinking about investing in real estate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On pretty much a weekly basis, we’re either asked, “How do I buy my first investment property?” or “How do I buy the next piece of real estate for my portfolio?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As lenders, we’ll typically look at three factors: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. We’ll look at your credit&lt;/strong&gt; to determine how many bills you pay, how much debt you have, and what your liabilities are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. We’ll look at your income&lt;/strong&gt;—both your own income, as well as what income the investment property would generate. Typically, better investment properties (i.e., the ones that have better cash flow) are found in desirable areas that are easy to market to renters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. We’ll look at what kind of down payment you can afford.&lt;/strong&gt; Most investment purchase programs will require a 20% down payment plus closing costs. For example, if you’re looking to buy a $300,000 condo, you can anticipate a $60,000 down payment to be able to begin the purchase process for that property. Sometimes there are other ways around it, such as when the seller wants to do private financing, but for institutional investors, this is a good baseline expectation to have. Some financial institutions might require more than 20% down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re ready to buy your first piece of investment property, we’d love to be the ones to provide you with guidance on how to accomplish your goals. Feel free to reach out to us so we can help you begin the process or answer any questions you have. We hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:22:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-factors-for-future-real-estate-investors-to-consider.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-factors-for-future-real-estate-investors-to-consider.html</guid>
        
        <category>Budgeting for a Home</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Difference Between APR and Interest Rates</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/T-gT_VrA7oA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knowing the difference between interest rates and annual percentage rates could save you thousands on your mortgage. Here’s what you need to know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between annual percentage rates (APR) and interest rates? &lt;strong&gt;Both rates measure important, but distinct, costs associated with your home loan,&lt;/strong&gt; and understanding the difference between the two could save you thousands on your mortgage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interest rate is the cost of borrowing the principal loan amount. It can be variable or fixed, but it’s always expressed as a percentage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The main difference between the two is that the interest rate calculates your actual monthly payment, while the APR calculates the total cost of your loan.%20http://localhost:4000/the-difference-between-apr-and-interest-rates.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The main difference between the two is that the interest rate calculates your actual monthly payment, while the APR calculates the total cost of your loan.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The annual percentage rate is a broader measure of the cost of your mortgage because it reflects the interest rate as well as other costs associated with your loans, such as lender fees, discount points, and some closing costs. The APR is also expressed as a percentage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main difference between the two is that the interest rate calculates your actual monthly payment, while the APR calculates the total cost of your loan. You can use one or both to make apples-to-apples comparisons when shopping for a loan. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re only focused on getting the lowest monthly payment, I’d focus on the interest rate,&lt;/strong&gt; but if you’re focused on the total cost of your loan, then you can use the APR as a tool to compare the total cost of two loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you found this information helpful! If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 08:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-difference-between-apr-and-interest-rates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-difference-between-apr-and-interest-rates.html</guid>
        
        <category>Budgeting for a Home</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How You Can Buy a Home With Zero Money Down</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UXi6z_lfh8s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t assume you can’t afford to buy a home. You can, and here’s how.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to buy a home but are worried you can’t afford it, I have good news: There are a few ways you can buy a home with 100% financing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is by &lt;strong&gt;using a VA loan&lt;/strong&gt;, which is reserved for veterans and active-duty members of the Armed Forces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second way you can purchase with 100% financing is by using PrimeLending’s &lt;strong&gt;Wealth Builder Program&lt;/strong&gt;.  This is an ARM product with a 20 or 15 year term - not a fixed product, which will help you reduce the principal on your loan fairly quickly (aka building wealth via equity). Keep in mind that some restrictions apply for this loan, and these restrictions pertain to what state you but in, your occupancy type, and your credit score and income. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are a few ways you can buy a home with 100% financing.%20http://localhost:4000/how-you-can-buy-a-home-with-zero-money-down.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are a few ways you can buy a home with 100% financing.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If neither of these options fit for you or you can afford to put a little money down, you can take advantage of &lt;strong&gt;conventional financing programs&lt;/strong&gt;, which allow a 97% loan-to-value rate on a 30-year fixed loan. Some FHA loan products allow up a 96.5% loan-to-value rate as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re curious whether any of these loans are right for you or you have any other real estate questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 08:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-you-can-buy-a-home-with-zero-money-down.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-you-can-buy-a-home-with-zero-money-down.html</guid>
        
        <category>First Time Homebuyer</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Do You Need to Get Approved for a Mortgage?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bhgOJY8FuKY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As your mortgage loan officer, I’ll need to gather some documentation from you to get you the best possible loan and interest rate. Here’s a list of the things that I’ll need.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home-buying journey should be simple and easy, and it’s my job to help you get prepared by providing you the tools and education to make the process smoother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we meet face to face, make sure you come prepared with your documentation so that I can do my part in providing you with all the different loan options you may be eligible for as a buyer. &lt;strong&gt;Here is a list of the documentation you should bring:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Your two most recent Federal Tax Returns,&lt;/strong&gt; including your W-2s, or your K-1s if you’re self-employed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Your two most recent pay stubs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Having this documentation is essential for all homebuyers.%20http://localhost:4000/what-do-you-need-to-get-approved-for-a-mortgage.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Having this documentation is essential for all homebuyers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your assets.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes all documentation relating to your savings accounts, checking accounts, 401(k), and other retirement account information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Your driver’s license, passport, and any other official ID.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job is to provide you with all the tools you need to map out a proper gameplan to help you succeed in your home purchase. &lt;strong&gt;You’ll end up feeling super confident so that you can start shopping and submitting offers with your real estate agent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 10:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-do-you-need-to-get-approved-for-a-mortgage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-do-you-need-to-get-approved-for-a-mortgage.html</guid>
        
        <category>First Time Homebuyer</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do Physician Home Loans Compare to Conventional Loans?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OaVdd4vF_VU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m often asked, “&lt;strong&gt;What is a doctor mortgage loan? And how does it compare to a conventional loan?&lt;/strong&gt;” This question holds a lot of relevance as some of us have friends and family who are finishing up graduate school and will potentially become first-time buyers. For that reason, I’d like to spell out some key differences between the two loan types today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what loan you’re considering, your lender will carefully examine three criteria: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your credit &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your income &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your collateral (or money available for the down payment or reserves) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with &lt;strong&gt;credit&lt;/strong&gt;, let’s discuss each point of consideration. To qualify for a physician loan, you’ll generally be required to have a credit score of 720 or higher, whereas the standard credit score requirement for conventional and government loan programs tends to be much lower; as a matter of fact, some can go as low as 580. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=No matter what loan you’re considering, your lender will carefully examine three criteria: your credit, your income, and your collateral.%20http://localhost:4000/how-do-physician-home-loans-compare-to-conventional-loans.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“No matter what loan you’re considering, your lender will carefully examine three criteria: your credit, your income, and your collateral.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second criterion on the list is &lt;strong&gt;income&lt;/strong&gt;. For doctor, physician, and preferred medical professional loan programs, your lender will look at one of two things: the income you’re receiving under your current employment contract or if you’ve yet to graduate but have a conditional offer of employment lined up, the starting income you’ll receive upon hire. That’s rarely the case with government or conventional programs; more often than not, they’ll want to see that you’ve been with the same employer for some length of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings us to our final factor: &lt;strong&gt;collateral&lt;/strong&gt;. With a physician loan, you can actually qualify for a $1 million loan amount with as little as 5% down. Plus, you won’t be required to purchase private mortgage insurance. As far as cash reserves go, your lender will check that you have at least six to nine months’ worth of payments at hand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conventional and government loans are quite a bit different here too. For example, once you pass the $729,000 threshold amount here in San Diego, your loan will be considered a jumbo loan, at which point the investor(s) will require a 20% down payment. On a $1 million home loan, putting 5% as opposed to 20% down is a massive difference—$50,000 versus $200,000. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that different investors go with different underwriting styles, so it’s best to meet with a service provider or mortgage professional who has ample experience working with physician loans. If you have any questions or would like more information, please let us know. We look forward to serving you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 09:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-physician-home-loans-compare-to-conventional-loans.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-do-physician-home-loans-compare-to-conventional-loans.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Loan Types</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Might Qualify for Less Than 20% Down</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wa0gLrKkmtU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A popular myth that circulates among buyers today is that you’ll need to put at least 20% down to qualify for a home purchase. If that were the case, a lot of buyers out there would have no shot at getting into a home and would end up living in a van down by the river. The reality is that mortgages don’t have blanket requirements. There are so many loan programs available that depend on your budget, credit score, where you want to live, etc. In fact, some programs require as little as 3%, and others are zero-down!  Down payment assistance programs also exist for certain buyers(1) . Our role is to set you up with the best possible mortgage on a home you truly love, and we’ll move mountains to make that happen for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like to go over your options, please contact us today by phone at 1-833-760-9979 or send us an email at SoCal@PrimeLending.com. We look forward to serving you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Disclaimers&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Certain restrictions apply. Not available in all areas. Please contact your PrimeLending loan officer for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 09:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/you-might-qualify-for-less-than-20-down.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/you-might-qualify-for-less-than-20-down.html</guid>
        
        <category>Budgeting for a Home</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
